Discover the mystery behind the legend.
Girl with a Pearl Earring is a drama, romance film directed by Peter Webber.
This film, adapted from a work of fiction by author Tracy Chevalier, tells a story about the events surrounding the
creation of the painting "Girl With A Pearl Earring" by 17th century Dutch master Johannes Vermeer.
A young peasant maid working in the house of painter Johannes Vermeer becomes his
talented assistant and the model for one of his most famous works.
Griet, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Johannes Vermeer, played by Colin Firth.
Pieter Van Ruijven, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Pieter, played by Cillian Murphy.
Maria Thins, played by Judy Parfitt.
Catharina Bolnes Vermeer, played by Essie Davis.
Girl with a Pearl Earring (Dutch: Meisje met de parel) is an oil painting
by Dutch Golden Age painter Johannes Vermeer, dated c.
Going by various names over the centuries, it acquired its
present title towards the end of the 20th century.
The work has been in the collection of the Mauritshuis in The Hague since 1902 and
has been the subject of various literary and cinematic treatments.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
painting, butcher, painter, biography.
The tone is emotional.